杰森:我喜欢这个,但是我通常是不喜欢音乐的,对吗,麦琪?
Jason: Well I loved it, and I generally don't like musicals, right Maggie?
麦琪: 哦,你喜欢滑稽服装.
Maggie: Oh you loved La Cage au Folles.
杰森:是,但是那不是用于音乐的;我喜欢穿衣服的人.
Jason: Yeah, but that wasn't for the music; I like men in dresses.
麦琪:杰森!
Maggie: Jason!
开萝尔:别看,但是那个可爱的服务生整晚都盯着我.
Carol: Don't anybody look,
哦,天哪,
but that cute waiter has been staring at me all night long.
他过来了……他过来了.嘘.
Oh my God, here he comes...here he comes.Shh.
服务生:如果你需要其它什么,任何东西,一声口哨就行了.
Waiter: If you need anything else, anything at all, just whistle.
杰森:那是理发.
Jason: It's the hair cut.
迈克:嗨,也许你应该给自己来个平头,开萝尔.
Mike: Hey, maybe you should get yourself a flat-top, Carol.
开萝尔:我们吃完甜点就回家.
Carol: Can we just finish our desserts and go home please.
麦琪:哦,别那样说,
Maggie: Oh, don't talk like that honey.
亲爱的.你刚看了百老汇最热的戏.
You just saw the hottest play on Broadway.
沃利:哦,你不喜欢吗?
Wally: Oh, that what it was?
欧玛:你不喜欢这戏!
Urma: You didn't like it!
沃利:戏很糟.
Wally: It blew.
杰森:但是我觉得是迷人的.
Jason: Well I thought it was fascinating.
沃利:你都流口水了.
Wally: You got some drool on your lip.
杰森:麦琪,你帮我解决吧.我为什么自找麻烦?咖啡!
Jason: Maggie, help me out here.Why do I even bother?Coffee!
麦琪:哦,亲爱的,你不需要再喝咖啡了.
Maggie: Oh, honey, you don't need any more coffee.
杰森:不,我不需要,可我想.
Jason: No, I don't need it, I want it.
麦琪:喝太多咖啡的话,你会整晚谁不着,
Maggie: Too much coffee and your up all night,
我们每个人都不应该这样.亲爱的,你知道我说的意思.
and neither one of us wants that.Honey, you know what I mean.
杰森:不,那很好,麦琪,
Jason: No, that's fine, Maggie, that's fine.
很好.如果你求我,我就不再喝咖啡了.
I wouldn't have more coffee now if you begged me.
欧玛:哎,我不知道为什么你怎么也去剧院了?
Urma: Well, I don't know why you even go to the theatre.
沃利:是因为你逼我去的.
Wally: Well, because you make me.
本:不算差.我喜欢洗澡那幕的女孩子.
Ben: It wasn't so bad.I liked the girls in the shower scene.
开萝尔:他们穿的是紧身衣,你这个小色鬼.
Carol: They were wearing tights, you little perverts.
本:紧身衣?哦,瞧,沃利说的对,这戏很糟.
Ben: They were?Oh, look, Wally's right, this play blew.
杰森,嗨,迈克,你学戏剧的,你怎么看?
Jason: Alright Mike, you're the drama student, what did you think?
迈克:那好,他们的紧身衣非常逼真,爸爸.
Mike: Well, they were pretty realistic tights, Dad.
欧玛:那好,我了我,你也得至少尝试着喜欢.
Urma: Well, you could have at least tried to enjoy it for me.
沃利:我已经尝试了.我偷着喝啤酒和干其他事情.
Wally: Well I did try.I snuck in beers and everything.
欧玛:我是认真的.
Urma: I'm serious.
沃利:好,好,
Wally: Well, fine, you wanna talk serious;
你想认真谈谈;你为什么不尝试喜欢我喜欢干的事情?
why don't you try enjoying the things I like?
欧玛:对不起,我不喜欢在家做香肠.
Urma: I'm sorry, I don't like making sausage at home.
沃利:是的,但是你一定喜欢吃吧.
Wally: Yeah, but you sure enjoying eating it.
欧玛:别对我提高嗓门.
Urma: Don't you raise your voice to me!
麦琪:沃利,欧玛,好了,人家看着呢.
Maggie: Wally, Urma, please, people are staring.
沃利:什么?你们从来就没有被老婆骂过吗?
Wally: What?You never been ragged on by a wife before?
麦琪:哦,你好,玛戈特.一切都好吧?
Maggie: Oh, hi Margot.Everything OK?
玛戈特:很好.克莉丝是个天使.
Margot:Great.Chrissy was an angel.
麦琪:哦,很好.开萝尔,有个小伙子找你.
Maggie: Oh, good.mar Oh, Carol, some guy called for you.
开萝尔:好呀,甚至连保姆都取笑我.玛戈特:我是认真的.
Carol: Right, even the babysitter makes fun of me. Margot: I'm serious.
本:你好,我是本 西维尔.
Ben: Hi, I'm Ben Seaver.
别说我们见过,两年之后,我不会这么个傻样了.
I don't believe we've met, and in two years I should out-grow this goofyness.
杰森:本,睡觉去.
Jason: Ben, go to bed.
本:我会去睡觉的.
Ben: You bet I will.
杰森:本!
Jason: Ben!
麦琪:给你,玛戈特.西维尔医生开车送你回家.
Maggie: Here you go, Margot.And Doctor Seaver will give you a ride home.
迈克:啊,不需要.不需要,
Mike: Ah, no need.No need, Mom.I'd be happy to take Margot home.mar Err...
妈妈.我乐意送玛戈特回家.玛戈特:喔……我家离这很远呀.
well it's quite a distance.
迈克:哦,没关系.再见,大伙.
Mike: Oh, I don't mind.See you guys.
杰森和麦琪:晚安.
Jason and Maggie: Good night.
迈克:晚安.
Mike: Good night.
杰森:啊,我想再次回到年轻.
Jason: Ah, to be young again.
麦琪:哦,亲爱的,你没那么老.
Maggie: Oh, honey, you're not that old.
杰森:哈.我没有说我自己.
Jason: Ha.I wasn't talking about me.
麦琪:什么?
Maggie: What?
杰森:我也没有说你.
Jason: I wasn't talking about you either.
麦琪:那么,你在说……
Maggie: Yes you were...
杰森:不,你是如此年轻…….
Jason: No, you're so young...
麦琪:你总是这样说……
Maggie: You're always doing this...
麦琪:打你!我打你!
Maggie: Got you!I got you!
杰森:哦,停下,停下,停下.
Jason: Oh, stop, stop, stop.
麦琪:哦,杰森.
Maggie: Oh, Jason.
杰森:哦,你弄疼我了.
Maggie: What, are you afraid of a little tickle?
麦琪:什么,你害怕挠痒痒?
Jason: Oh, you're hurting me.
杰森:不是了,我怕你会压碎我的腿.
Jason: No, I'm afraid you're gonna crush my legs.
麦琪:哦,亲爱的,你自找的.
Maggie: Oh, honey, you're asking for it.
杰森:是呀,以我自己独特的方式.
Jason: Yeah, in my own special way.
麦琪:哦,当你傻乎乎的时候还是可爱的.
Maggie: Oh, you're kind of cute when you're stupid.
杰森:哦,是呀,那样你会……发疯.
Jason: Oh, yeah, then this is gonna be...crazy.
麦琪:我们的婚姻真的到了这种地步?
Maggie: Has our marriage really come to this?
杰森:我认为早就这样了.
Jason: I think quite a while ago.
麦琪:哦,但是你今晚很闹腾.
Maggie: Oh, but you're so frisky tonight.
杰森:是这样,我带我的家人去去享受戏剧和晚餐的美好夜晚,
Jason: Well, I just treated my family to a wonderful evening of theatre
会使一个男人感到自豪.
and dinner, it makes a man proud.
麦琪:哦,亲爱的,我不认为你妈妈和沃利玩的开心.
Maggie: Oh, honey, I don't think your mom and Wally had so much fun.
杰森:是呀,我那时感觉到了一点紧张氛围.
Jason: Yeah, I sensed a little tension there.
麦琪:紧张!他们都准备把对方的脾给撕出来.
Maggie: Tension!They were ready to rip each other's spleens out.
杰森:对.哈哈哈.
Jason: Yeah.Ha ha ha.
麦琪:你对此很开心,是吗?
Maggie: You're happy about this, aren't you?
杰森:不,不,我不开心,
Jason: No, no, I'm not happy, Maggie.I'm just kidding around.
麦琪.我只是开个玩笑.我是说,
I mean, if I thought that my mother were ever gonna be hurt,
如果我认为我妈妈受到什么伤害,如果她真的遇上什么困难,
if ever there were any real problems there with her, well, I don't know,
那,我不知道,我不知道我会做些什么.
I don't know what I'd do.
麦琪:你知道,亲爱的,沃利确实真是个好人.
Maggie: You know, honey, Wally really is a pretty good guy.
杰森:对.但是对于我妈妈来说,他还不够好.
Jason: Yeah.Well he's not good enough for my mom.
麦琪:那么谁够好?
Maggie: Well who would be?
杰森:我爸爸……愿他的灵魂安息.(电话响)喂.哦,你好妈妈.
Jason: My Dad...rest his soul.(Phone rings) Hello.Oh, hi Mom.
对,不,我们正准备……恩?今晚?好的,
Yeah, no, we were just getting ready...Huh?Tonight?
不,我马上到.好的.再见.
OK, no, I'll be right there.Alright.Bye.
麦琪: 怎么了?
Maggie: What is it?
杰森: 她要离开沃利
Jason: She's leaving Wally.
麦琪:什么?
Maggie: What?
杰森:她要我去接她.麦琪,
Jason: She wants me to come right over and pick her up.
太糟了.
Maggie, this is terrible.
麦琪:哦,亲爱的,我们能干什么呢?
Maggie: Oh, honey, what are we gonna do?
杰森:我们做爱.
Jason: Let's make love.
麦琪:这和这事有什么关系?
Maggie: What's that got to do with anything?
杰森:为什么不只说好,我会找到联系起来的方法的.
Jason: Why not just say yes, and I'll find a way to tie it in?
麦琪:哦.
Maggie: Oh.
电视:这就结束我们今天的节目.先别关掉电视,
TV: This concludes our broadcasting day.
罗赞 芭小姐将演唱国歌.
Stay tuned for the National Anthem by Miss Rosanne Bar.
麦琪:结束了.
Maggie: That was close.
欧玛:那么,
Urma: Well, let's see how he survives on his own.
看看他自己怎么活.瞧瞧他没有干净内衣怎么办.
Let's see what he does without his clean underwear.
瞧瞧他是否找得到他的假牙.
Let's see if he can find his teeth.
杰森:哦,妈妈,
Jason: Oh, Mom, you're exaggerating.
你太夸张了.我想沃利找到自己的假牙是不成问题的.
I'm sure Wally won't have any trouble finding his teeth.
麦琪:欧玛,这事也许我不该过问,
Maggie: Urma, this may not be my place but it was just an argument in
但是那只是在饭店里面的斗嘴呀.
a restaurant.
欧玛:这不只是斗嘴.
Urma: It wasn't just this argument.
然道你从来就没有那样的想法,
Don't you ever have a moment where it occurs to you that you're married
你嫁错了人.
to the wrong person?Maggie and Jason: Oh, it's only natural.
麦琪和杰森:哦,这是自然的.
Maggie and Jason: Oh, it's only natural.
欧玛:恩,关键问题在于我们绝对没有共同之处.
Urma: Well, it just points out that we have absolutely nothing in common.
麦琪:哦,欧玛,
Maggie: Oh, Urma, well you're welcome to stay here and live here with
只要你喜欢,你可以和我们住在这,多长时间都可以.
us as long as you want to.
欧玛:两天就行了.
Urma: Two days should do it.
麦琪:什么?
Maggie: Pardon me?
欧玛:啊,你们以为好象我要离婚一样.
Urma: Well you people act as if I'm headed for divorce.
杰森:哦.我……我……我糊涂了.
Jason: Oh, I...I...I'm confused.
欧玛:什么糊涂了?他过两天的独自生活,
Urma: What's confusing?Two days on his own will teach him that life's
就会告诉他,有人管着的日子还是不错的.
not so bad on a short lease.
麦琪:那么,你们没有决裂!
Maggie: So, you're not splitting up!
欧玛:他也不是全糟透了.而且他的浪漫也……很不错.
Urma: It hasn't been all bad.And the romance department is...quite nice.
杰森:哦,妈妈,行了!
Jason: Oh Mom, please!
欧玛:哦,我的婚姻会很完美,
Urma: Oh, my marriage would be perfect if only I could get him to change...
如果我如果能使得他改变……完全地.
completely.
麦琪和杰森:我们听着呢.
Maggie and Jason: Oh, I hear you.
欧玛:哦,杰森,你能否再帮我一个忙,亲爱的.
Urma: Oh, Jason, could you do me one more favour dear.
杰森:好的,说吧.
Jason: Yeah, name it.
欧玛:这样,我已经整理了几个袋子,
Urma: Well, I've packed a couple more bags back at the apartment,
放在家里,为了有戏剧性的效果.
for the dramatic effect.
明天你去市里面的时候,你可以把它们带回来吗?
When you're in the city tomorrow, could you pick them up for me please?
杰森:行.
Jason: Yeah.
欧玛:我想,当他看你拿走东西时,
Urma: I think when he sees you pick them up,
他屁股都会气的变形,像法式脆饼.
that will put a twist in his lower tract like a Bovarian Pretzel.
各位,晚安.
Good night all.
麦琪:多么可爱的夫人.
Maggie: What a lovely woman.
杰森:麦琪,你得从各个角度去看待这个问题.
Jason: Well you have to put this in perspective, Maggie.
我是说,她都已经可爱到不去接受事实…….她得改改.
I mean, she's so sweet that she can't admit the truth...she has to repress it.
麦琪:哦,那么事实是什么?
Maggie: Oh, and what truth is that?
杰森:那就是,她得摆脱那个家伙,
Jason: That she should be rid of that guy, right now.
现在.把对于他的记忆从我们中抹去.
That the memory of him should be erased from all of us.
麦琪:那么也许我应该是那个取衣箱的.
Maggie: Well maybe I should be the one to go pick up the suitcases.
杰森:哦,你认为我不客观!
Jason: Oh, you think I can't be objective!
麦琪:是的.
Maggie: Yes.
杰森:你对我判断错误.享用面条吧,沃利.而且顺便说句,这假牙你愿意用多久就多久.
Jason: You misjudge me so.je Enjoy the lasagne, Wally.And by the way, keep
the teeth as long as you like
杰森:啊哈!杰瑞 沃利!哪里?哪里?
Jason: Ah ha!Jerry Vale!Where?Where?
沃利:嗨 杰瑞,很合身……
Wally: Hey Jerry, they fit flat...
杰森:喂,沃.
Jason: Hi Wal.
沃利:你来干什么,你这个庸医?
Wally: What do you want, you quack?
杰森:不需要骂人吧,沃利.
Jason: No need for name-calling, Wally.
沃利:这样的话,我跟你没什么好说的.
Wally: Well then, I got nothing more to say to you.
杰森:我只是过来拿走我妈妈的东西.
Jason: I just came by to get some of my mother's things!
沃利:想把我的屁股气成羊腿,是吗?
Wally: This is supposed to twist my lower tract into a sheep shank, right?
杰森:正确的说是法式脆饼.
Jason: Actually a Bovarian Pretzel.
沃利:好吧,进来吧.你喜欢这样,是吧?
Wally: Well, come on in.You just love this, don't you?
杰森:绝对不,沃利.
Jason: Absolutely not, Wally.
沃利:那么,告诉她我过的很好,
Wally: Well, tell her I'm sitting pretty,
用杰瑞 沃莉的内衣和假牙.
with Jerry Vale's underwear and teeth.
杰森:我会告诉她.她的带子呢?
Jason: I'll tell her that.Where are the bags?
沃利:在那.而且你可以告诉她,
Wally: Over there.And you can tell her from me, her little plan didn't work.
她的小把戏没用.我不会被她管制.
I'm not gonna kept on a short leash.
杰森:你真的认为我妈妈是这样的人.
Jason: You actually think my mother's like that.
沃利:嚯嚯嚯.整天我所听到的就是,
Wally: Ho ho ho.
别吃那,别穿那,
All day long I hear, don't eat that, oh don't wear that,
还有去看戏怎么样?
well don't you wanna go to the theatre?
见鬼,不,
Hell no, I don't wanna go to the theatre.
我可不想去看戏.我喜欢看球赛和吃零食.
I wanna watch a ball game and eat a brod!
杰森:是这样,她只是希望你能更好,沃利.
Jason: Well, she's only looking out for you best interests, Wally.
沃利:那么我不再被这样的女人操控.
Wally: Well I will not be manipulated by that woman.
杰森:这样的事情总是会发生的.你知道,在婚姻里,
Jason: Well these things happen all the time.
夫妻要同舟共济,可是突然之间,吹灭了.
You know, a couple's sailing along in a marriage and all of a sudden, pooft!
沃利:什么吹灭了?
Wally: What pooft?
杰森:这个吹灭了!
Jason: This pooft!
沃利:谁吹灭的?
Wally: Who pooft?
杰森:你吹灭的!
Jason: You pooft!
沃利:我可没有吹灭.
Wally: I didn't poof!
杰森:吹灭了.
Jason: Poof!
沃利:如果有人吹灭,是你妈妈吹灭的!
Wally: If anybody pooft, your mother pooft!
杰森:收回这样的话,沃利.
Jason: You take that back, Wally.
沃利:啊,我就站在这里跟一个跑差的人说话?
Wally: Ah, what am I doing here standing for talking to an errand boy?
杰森:一个跑差的小子!
Jason: An errand boy!
沃利:恩.
Wally: Mmm.
杰森:行了,还有一件差事,沃利.妈妈要这房子的委托书.
Jason: Alright, one more errand, Wally.
沃利:那么她要那个干什么?
Wally: Well what does she want that for?
杰森:这,我不知道.谁知道这些事情发展到什么地步呢?
Jason: Well, I don't know.Who knows where these things could lead?
沃利:你说什么呢?
Wally: What are you saying?
杰森:我什么都没说,沃利.我是精神病医生,不是律师.
Jason: I'm not saying anything, Wally.
沃利:律师!她找律师了!
Wally: Lawyer!She's getting a lawyer!
杰森:这,嗯……对,委托书的事情过一两天再说.
Jason: Well, err...yeah, the papers can wait for a day or two.
听着,我只是拿走这些带子,你吃你的面吧.
Look, I'm just gonna take these bags, and you finish your lasagne.
沃利:哦,突然之间我不饿了.杰森,我对这个太熟悉了.
Wally: Oh, suddenly I'm not so hungry.Jason, I'm too old for this.
杰森:什么?
Jason: Pardon me?
沃利:这样,如果她谈到律师和房屋委托书的话……
Wally: Well, if she's talking lawyers and condo papers...
杰森:这样,也许我夸张了点.也许我说过了点.
Jason: Well, I might have exaggerated a little.Maybe I got carried away here.
沃利:哦,不,不,现在不行,杰森;我的肠子在乱动.
Wally: Oh, no, no, no more right now Jason; my colon's dancing.
欧玛:杰森!
Urma: Jason!
克莉丝:不,奶奶,只是我们.
Chrissy: No Grandma, it's just us.
本:你叫她.
Ben: You ask her.
克莉丝:不.你.你比我认识她时间长.
Chrissy: No.You.You've known her longer.
本:瞧,奶奶,
Ben: Look, Grandma, you can't sit around her moping all day.
你不能整天闷闷不乐地无所事事.你想要投篮吗?
You wanna shoot some hoops?
欧玛:啊,那很好,亲爱的.不了,谢谢.
Urma: Ah, that's very sweet, dear.No thank you.
本:啊,我们已经提议了.尽力了.
Ben: Ah, we made the offer.That takes care of that.
开萝尔:奶奶,我听说了你和沃利的事情.
Carol: Grandma, I heard about you and Wally.This is the worst thing.
最糟糕的事情了.我很担心,
I have been so upset, I haven't been able to sleep or eat.
我睡不着和吃不下.这是我的口信.来自一个男孩……昨晚.
This message is for me.It's from a boy...last night.
奶奶,为什么没人告诉我?
Well, Grandma, why didn't anybody tell me?
欧玛:对不起,亲爱的.我猜是我太全神贯注了.
Urma: I'm sorry dear, I guess I was just a little preoccupied.
开萝尔:哦,一定.哦,一定,就考虑自己.
Carol: Oh, sure.Oh sure, just think of yourself.
麦琪: 开萝尔在嚷什么?
Maggie: What was Carol shouting about?
欧玛:她在安慰我……我认为.哦,
Urma: She was comforting me...I think.
杰森,你去拿带子,他有什么反应?
Oh, Jason, how did he take it when you picked up the bags?
杰森:是这样……
Jason: Well...
欧玛:很伤心?
Urma: Was he devastated?
杰森:这,我不……
Jason: Well, I don't...
欧玛:这……麦琪,让你老公说话.
Urma: Well...Maggie, get your husband to talk.
麦琪:杰森,说!
Maggie: Jason, talk!
杰森:这,行李的事情没用.妈妈,他太了解你了.
Jason: Well, the luggage thing didn't work.He's onto you Mother.
欧玛:哦,他如此了解我.他不看起来聪明.
Urma: Oh, he knows me so well.He's smarter than he looks.
杰森:因此,为了坚持你的计划的精神.
Jason: So, in keeping with the spirit of your plan.
我让他拿出房子财产委托书.
I asked him to turn over the papers to the condo.
欧玛:哦,我的儿子,我把你教育的不错.
Urma: Oh, my son, I have traied you well.
杰森:你不会相信.我们开始谈论,
Jason: You have no idea.
从一件到另外一件,
We started talking, one thing led to another, and before I know it,
最后我才知道,我请求我帮助你们再次回到一起.
he was asking me to help you two get back together again.
欧玛:你!但是你不能忍受沃利!
Urma: You!But you can't stand Wally!
杰森:我知道.我知道.我告诉他这些了.他说没关系.
Jason: I know.I know.I told him that.He said it didn't matter.
他说,他所在意的,我是个诚实的人.
He said, as far as he's concerned, I'm an honest man.
欧玛:他戴假牙,说假话.
Urma: Then he was lying through his teeth.
杰森:事实上,杰瑞 沃莉的假牙.嗨,沃利真的很生气.
Jason: Actually, Jerry Vale's teeth.Hey, Wally's really upset.
欧玛:你确定?
Urma: Are you sure?
杰森:嗨,有一大盘子面,他一点都吃不了.
Jason: Hey, there was a whole plate of lasagne there, he couldn't eat a bite.
欧玛:面条是他的最爱.我不再为他做了……永远.
Urma: Lasagne's his favourite food.I won't cook it for him...ever.
杰森:瞧,她说他认为我是他最后的机会….
Jason: Look, he said that he thought I was his last chance to...
来解决问题,否则你们两个会失去一切的.
work things out, or you two would lose everything.
欧玛:哦,亲爱的.这比我预想的要严重.哦,我做什么了?
Urma: Oh dear.This is more serious than I thought.Oh, what have I done?
麦琪:对……对不起,欧玛.杰森,你做什么了?
Maggie: E...excuse me, Urma.Jason, what have you done?
杰森:没什么.我甚至告诉沃利,
Jason: Nothing.I even told Wally,
那房屋委托书是我的主意,不是妈妈的主意.
that the idea for the papers and the condo that was mine, not Mom's.
麦琪:这些事情告诉我,你意气用事了.
Maggie: Well something tells me that you were'nt that objective.]
杰森:麦琪.在那屋子没有发生让我感到羞愧的事情,
Jason: Maggie.Nothing went on in that apartment that I'm ashamed of, alright?
好了吧?除了可能那个吹灭的事情.
Except maybe that poof thing.
麦琪:什么吹灭的事情?
Maggie: What poof thing?
杰森:别让我再说那事.
Jason: Don't even get me started on that.
欧玛:(通电话)你好,沃利,是我.听着,我正考虑……什么?
Urma: (On the phone) Hi Wally, it's me.Listen, I was thinking that...What?
哦,好吧.恩……再见.看来他不想跟我谈谈,他太生气了.
Oh, yes.Err...goodbye.Says he can't talk to me, he's so upset.
麦琪:哦,欧玛,
Maggie: Oh Urma, you two obviously love each other,
你们两个很明显是爱着对方的,否则你们就不会这样相互折磨了.
or you wouldn't be putting each other throught this hell.
欧玛:我们甚至不能再相互说话了.
Urma: We can't even talk to each other any more.
杰森:也许你是需要时间来使得事情冷静下了,妈妈.
Jason: Maybe what you need is just a little time to let things cool off, Mom.
欧玛:我所需要的就是你的帮助.如果沃利能够依靠他憎恨的人,我也能.
Urma: What I need is your help.
杰森:什么?
Jason: Pardon me?
麦琪:欧……欧……欧玛,我认为,
Maggie: U...U...Urma, I think that maybe what you and Wally need to do is...
也许你和沃利所要做的是……是看专家.
is see a professional.
欧玛:我不需要专家.我需要我儿子.
Urma: I don't want a professional.I want my son.
杰森:嗨,嗨,听着,我可不想搀和其中,妈妈.
Jason: Hey, hey, look, I don't want to get in the middle of this, Mom.
欧玛:那么你在去取我箱子之前就应该想过这点.
Urma: Well you should of thought of that before you volunteered to go
pick up my suitcases.
麦琪:杰森,我爱你.
Maggie: Jason, I love you.
但是请不要自私,你是个骗子,你知道吗?
And please don't take this personally, but you're a lying sack, you know that?
杰森:亲爱的 ,你没有听明白我刚才说的话.
Jason: Honey, you didn't hear what I just said.
我不想搀和这件事情.
I don't wanna get caught in the middle of this thing!
麦琪:杰森,你不会告诉我,
Maggie: Jason, you can't tell me that you weren't thrilled your mother
当你妈妈端着枪,装着上面写着沃利名字的子弹,你都不会发抖.
handed you a gun loaded with bullet with Wally's name on it.
杰森:我有点伤心,麦琪,
Jason: I'm a little hurt, Maggie,
这样我妈妈比你更加正确地了解我.
that my mother sees me more clearly right now, than you do.
麦琪::哦,这怎么说?
Maggie: Oh, and how's that.
杰森:这样,她完全准备依靠她的诚实,
Jason: Well, she's fully prepared to rely on her honest and fair and
工整和客观的儿子.
objective son.
麦琪:哦!我认为你只是一个小孩子.
Maggie: Oh!I thought you were an only child.
欧玛:沃利现在应该已经到这了.你确定告诉他七点?
Urma: Wall should be here by now.Are you sure you told him seven o' clock?
沃利:有人开门吗?
Wally: Will somebody open this darn door.
欧玛:让他等会.
Urma: Let him wait a minute.
麦琪:你们两个谁去开门?
Maggie: Are either of you gonna open the door?
杰森:还有40秒.
Jason: Forty seconds to go.
麦琪::沃利,见到你真好.
Maggie: Wally, it's good to see you.
沃利:你好,欧玛.
Wally: Hi Urma.
欧玛:你好,沃利.哦,你看起来不一样了.
Urma: Hi Wally.Oh, you look different.
沃利:是的,这是假牙.
Wally: Yes, it's the teeth.
麦琪:哦,坐下吧?
Maggie: Oh, would you like to sit?
沃利:坐!我还以为我们准备躺下做点什么呢.
Wally: Sit!Well I thought we were supposed to lie down and do things.
杰森:哈!不,不,这样安静是不起作用的,沃利.事情是这样的,我跟你们都已经分别谈,然后我们一起谈.
Jason: Ha!No no, it doesn't work quite like that, Wally.What happens is, I
talk to each of you individually and then we all talk together
沃利:你先.
Wally: You first.
欧玛:不,你先.
Urma: No, you first.
沃利:不,在你后面.
Wally: No, after you.
欧玛:哦,你先讲;我有严重的问题.
Urma: Oh, you should go first; you have a serious problem.
沃利:你先讲,因为你是个严重的问题.
Wally: You should go first because you are the serious problem.
杰森:嗨,嗨,嗨,嗨,嗨,嗨,嗨.我决定.沃利,你先讲.
Jason: Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey.Hey.I'll decide.Wally, you're going first.
沃利:好呀,你选择站在你妈妈一边.
Wally: Well, it figures you'd side with your mother.
杰森:我不偏向谁,沃利.好了,你先说.
Jason: I'm not taking sides, Wally.OK, you go first.
沃利:哦,不,你说我先,我就先说.
Wally: Oh, no, you said me first, I'm going first.
杰森:好,好,沃利.进我办公室.
Jason: Fine, Fine, Wally.Step into my office.
沃利:哦,哦,
Wally: Oh, oh no.
不.
I'm not going into some office and laying on a couch where some crazy
我不会去你那个办公室,躺在一些疯子躺过的沙发上.
people have been.
杰森:沃利,你认为精神疾病是一种病毒吗?
Jason: Wally, you think mental illness is a virus?
沃利:恩,从我的角度看,在这里是传染病.
Wally: Well, from where I'm standing it looks pretty much hereditory.
麦琪:瞧,我有个主意.
Maggie: Err, look, I've got an idea.
为什么不你和沃利在这里谈,我和欧玛去厨房呢?
Why don't you and Wally talk here and Urma and I can go in the kitchen.
沃利:很好.
Wally: Good.
杰森:沃利.
Jason: Wally.
沃利:我把头放在哪端?
Wally: Which end do I put my head on?
杰森:没关系.
Jason: Doesn't matter.
沃利:我也是这么想的.
Wally: I figured as much.
杰森:你不必躺下来,沃利.
Jason: You don't have to lie down, Wally.
沃利:我能来杯啤酒吗?
Wally: Well can I have a beer?
杰森:沃利,行了,
Jason: Wally, come on, let's just concentrate on why you're here.
我们把问题集中在你来这里干什么的.
I'd like you to talk about your marriage to my Mom,
我希望你谈谈你和我妈妈的婚姻,你对这些问题怎么看的?
and what you think are the problems.
沃利:很糟!
Wally: It blows!
杰森:能具体点吗?
Jason: Can you be a little more specific?
沃利:糟透了!有时我认为她在努力把我转变成她所想象的结婚的时候的那样,但是我不是那样的,因为我们相互献殷勤.整天……
Wally: It blows chunks!Sometimes I think she's trying to turn me into the person she thought I was when we were married, but I wasn't, 'cause we were courting.All day long...
杰森:(在想)瞧他坐在那,向我吐露真言……好象我在乎.
Jason: (in his head) Look at him sitting there pouring his guts out to me...
等等,我应该在乎,
like I care.Wait I do care, I'm a professional.
我是专家.他们婚姻的重量在我手里,
The weight of their marriage is in my hands,
我不应该想这些事情.我应该听他说的每个词.
I shouldn't be thinking these things.I should be listening to his every word.
沃利:还有为什么我要依靠杰瑞 沃莉端给我面条?
Wally: And why should I rely on Jerry Vale to bring me my lasagne?
杰森:(在想)我停止思考,听他说!
Jason: (in his head) And I stopped thinking to hear that!
杰森:哦,你不必躺下,妈妈.
Jason: Oh, you don't have to lay down, Mom.
欧玛:沃利躺下的吗?
Urma: Did Wally lay down?
杰森:没有,他坐着.
Jason: No, he sat.
欧玛:那么我就躺下.
Urma: Then I'll lay down.
杰森:妈妈.
Jason: Mom.
欧玛:什么?
Urma: What?
杰森:你应该说点什么.
Jason: You're supposed to talk.
欧玛:哦,我认为你应该说点什么.
Urma: Oh, I thought you were supposed to talk.
杰森:不,不.这是工作程序,你说,我听.
Jason: No, no.The way this works is, you talk, I listen.
欧玛:你是说,
Urma: You mean, you spent all those years in that expensive medical school,
你花了那么多年时间在那所昂贵的医学院里学习,就是为了呆坐在那听人说话?
just to sit there like a bump in a log to listen?
这么说,
Well, I'm used to talking and nobody talking back...
我已经习惯说话,
that's what it's like being with Wally.
但是没人搭理了……这点跟沃利也这样.只要电视家庭购物指南一介绍女子贴身内衣,
And if the home shopping network has their lingerie bonanza on,
沃利整晚都不说话.
Wally's speechless the whole night.
杰森:(在想)可怜的女人.为什么会看不出沃利根本不适合她.这就像我希望马上跟麦琪上床一样.呵呵,这真有趣,每次我一想到我妈的婚姻危机,我就想跟麦琪上床.我可以就此写篇论文……或者一本书……名扬天下.等等,我走神了.还是专注于这里的重要事情吧.那不过是篇论文,还不够写本书.不,不,主题是我妈.好好听这个女人在说什么.她就依靠我了.
Jason: (in his head) The poor woman.Why can't she see how wrong Wally is for her.It's as obvious to me as the fact that I'd love to go to bed with Maggie right now.Boy, that's interesting, everytime I think of my mom's marriage breaking up, I wanna go to bed with Maggie.I could write a paper on that...maybe get on Donnahew...Operah.Wait a minute, I'm drifting.Let me stick to what's important here.It's just a paper, I don't have enough for a book.No, no, the subject's my mom.Listen to what the woman is saying.She's counting on me.
欧玛:而且他经常把面条往我脸上扔.
Urma: And he's always throwing Jerry Vale's lasagne in my face.
杰森:(在想)行了,我已经在外面待了二十分钟,
Jason: (in his head) OK, I've been out here twenty minutes,
给出一些真正认真的想法.哈哈!
giving this some really serious thought.Ha ha!
我能破坏这婚姻,没人比我更聪明了.
I could torpedo this marriage and no-one would be the wiser.
麦琪:杰森.
Maggie: Jason.
杰森:我在思考.麦琪……哦,天呀,你穿这件衣服真漂亮.
Jason: I'm done thinking.Maggie...oh boy, you look great in that dress.
麦琪:谢谢你,亲爱的.你妈妈和沃利怎么样了?
Maggie: Thank you honey.What about your mom and Wally?
杰森:这样,我摆脱他……我是说,
Jason: Well, I get rid of him...
我先帮助他,我会处理好的.
I mean, I'm gonna help him first, I'll take care of this.
以后的几分钟内,
For the next few moments I would like you both to think of me,
我让你们俩别把我当作你儿子,或者不屑一顾的人,
not as your son, and not as someone you despise, but as a professional,
而是专家,因为我要给你们我的专业建议.
because I wanna give you my professional opinion.(in his head) Think they
(在想)想象他们会吃这一套?没问题,
bought that?Yipper dipper they did.(spoken) Now, in any marriage,
他们会.
no matter how much love is involved,
(讲话)现在,每个婚姻中,
or how much love you think you have for one another,
无论其中包含了多少爱,或者你们觉得你们多么深爱对方,
there's also a practical side of the relationship.There's that...
婚姻关系总是有其十分现实的一面.那就是……那种关系取决于当事人双方在各方面是基本协调,
there's that bond that depends on a basic compatability or incompatability
还是不协调.
of the people involoved.(in his head) Oh, man,
(讲话)还有,恩……你们两个……就你们两个,
she's crossing her legs.(spoken) And err...you two...with you two, there's...
存在一些不协调,而且我觉得问题是……
there's some incompatability and I see the problem as...
克莉丝:妈妈!妈妈!
Chrissy: Mommy!Mommy!
麦琪:哦,怎么了,小甜心?
Maggie: Oh, what is it, sweetheart?
克莉丝:奶奶和沃利必须在一起.
Chrissy: Grandma and Wally have to stay together.
麦琪:哦,亲爱的,无论发生什么,他们都会仍然爱你.
Maggie: Oh, honey, no matter what happens, they'll both still love you.
克莉丝:对,对,
Chrissy: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
对.我要求奶奶离开我的房间,那样我可以开着灯睡觉了.
I just want Grandma out of my room so I can sleep with the light on.
杰森:等会儿;你所需要的要比对于他们重要的事情还要重要?
Jason: So wait a minute;
what you want is more important than what's good for them?
克莉丝:是.
Chrissy: Yep.
杰森:那么你不觉得自己自私吗?
Jason: Well aren't you being just a little bit selfish?
麦琪:你说什么呢,杰森?
Maggie: What did you say, Jason?
杰森:你不觉得自己自私吗?
Jason: Aren't you being a little bit selfish?
麦琪:你说什么呢,杰森?
Maggie: What did you say, Jason?
克莉丝:他问我是否有点自私.而我的答案是……
Chrissy: He asked me if I was being a little bit selfish.And the answer is...
杰森:是.是.
Jason: Yes.Yes.
沃利:我们就听听你有什么坏消息,行吗?
Wally: Let's just get to the bad news, OK?
杰森:我想很明显,就你们之间存在的所有不同点而言……那么,
Jason: Well I think it's obvious that with all the differences that exist
你们应该在一起.
between you...Well, you should stay together.
欧玛和沃利:什么?
Urma and Wally: What?
杰森:因为你们谁都没有足够的感觉去不爱对方.
Jason: Well because neither one of you has enough sense not to love each other.
沃利:啊?
Wally: Huh?
杰森:明白了.
Jason: You heard me.
欧玛:但是你所说的一切,都听起来像是我们应该放弃.
Urma: But everything you said, made it sound like we should give it up.
杰森:对,那是我也出现了问题.
Jason: Yeah, well I got problems of my own.
你们看着办吧,我出去呼吸新鲜空气.
You sort this out, I gotta get some fresh air.
麦琪:杰森.
Maggie: Jason.
杰森:什么?
Jason: What?
麦琪:我爱你.
Maggie: I love you.
杰森:怎么回事?
Jason: What's that for?
麦琪:因为你没有像四岁的女儿那样自私.
Maggie: For not being as selfish as your four year old daughter.
杰森:行了.
Jason: Come on.You actually think for a second I'd actually put my own
你真的一时认为我会把自己的需求放在首位?
needs first?
麦琪:是.但是内心里,我知道你会做对的.
Maggie: Yep.But deep down, I knew you'd do the right thing.
杰森:是,是,是,是.
Jason: Yep, yep, yep, yep.
麦琪:行了.你不要再猜疑自己了.你做对了.
Maggie: Come on.You can't second guess yourself.You did what was right.
欧玛:哦,沃利.你说话呀.
Urma: Oh, Wally, you cut that out.
沃利:哦,欧玛,我们去看一个你十分喜爱的无聊的话剧,怎么样?
Wally: Oh, Urma what do you say we see one of those boring plays you like so much?
欧玛:去看小女人贴身内衣怎么样?
Urma: What do you say to a little lingerie bonanza.
沃利:哦,欧玛,我放弃整个购物广播了.
Wally: Oh, Urma, I'm through with the whole shopping network.
欧玛:我没有谈电视.
Urma: I wasn't talking about TV.
沃利:哦!
Wally: Oh!
杰森:你不觉得肉麻吗?
Jason: Doesn't that make you wanna puke?
麦琪:你知道,亲爱的,
Maggie: You know honey, we don't have to wait for them to leave.We can...
我们没有必要等到他们离开.我们可以……现在上床睡觉.
turn in now.
杰森:(在想)有点太迟了,我没有那情趣.
Jason: (in his head) Too little too late, I'm not in the mood.
迈克:嗨,大伙.
Mike: Hey guys.
杰森:迈克,你去哪里了?
Jason: Mike, where have you been.
迈克:我送那个保姆了.
Mike: I've been dropping off the babysitter.
马激:但是她昨天晚上离开的.
Maggie: But she left last night.
迈克:我知道.她在辛辛那提.
Mike: I know.She lives in Sinsinatty.
克莉丝:你看起来是那种喜欢睡前故事的家伙.
Chrissy: You look like the kind of guy who'd enjoy a good bed-time story.
老鼠先生找到了家.
Mr.Mouse Finds a Home.
迈克:对不起,克莉丝,但是迈克先生找到了金发碧眼的女人.
Mike: Sorry, Chrissy, but Mr.Mike found a blonde.
克莉丝:我可从来没有见过六只脚的老鼠.
Chrissy: I've never seen six foot mouse before.
麦琪:小甜心,你在跟谁说话呢?
Maggie: Sweetheart, who are you talking to?
克莉丝:啊!
Chrissy: Aarrgh!!
麦琪:什么?
Maggie: What?
克莉丝:你是小热场乐队一员.
Chrissy: You're a little spooler shtoon.
麦琪:我也是个热场乐队一员.
克莉丝:对不起.他们说,一些健康的东西对你来说更重要.
00:22:48,800
Maggie: I am a smoosh too. Chrissy: Sorry.They said something healthy was better for you.